# William Arenas

Bellevue, WA ■ (253) 985-7989 ■ william\_arenas@hotmail.com

LinkedIn Profile: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/warenas">www.linkedin.com/in/warenas</a>

#### SUMMARY

**IT Management & Support Specialist** with an extensive track record of success supporting a wide range of corporate technology and computing needs, both in a W2 and Contract capacity. Recognized throughout career for exceptional troubleshooting, interpersonal, and project management skills.

# TECHNOLOGY/SOFTWARE PROFICIENCY

**PLATFORMS**: Windows Server 2003/2008, Windows 2000 Server, Windows NT Server 4.0,

Novell 4.11, AS/400

**SOFTWARE**: Microsoft Exchange Server 2010, 0365/MS Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Outlook

Express, SharePoint, Microsoft Family Safety, Acronis Backup

**O/S:** Windows 10, Windows 8, Windows 7, Windows Vista, Windows XP Professional,

Windows 2000 Pro, Windows ME, Windows 98, Windows 95, MS DOS 6.2

**NETWORKING&HARDWARE:** 

PC Compatibles, Laptops, MACs, Routers, Switches, cabling (Cat5, Cat6), T1, Modems, Wi-Fi, Printers (Matrix, Ink, Laser, Thermal, Multifunction, 3D and Copier), Scanners, Office Equipment, Docking Stations, Mobile Devices, AP, Security Cameras, Patch Panel, Phone System (DMARC, Punch Block),

Audio/Video System, VoIP, TCP/IP

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

IT Coordinator & Project Manager | ASSOCIATED RECREATION COUNCIL Seattle, WA: Dec 2014 - Present

- Responsible for the design, implement, maintain, and monitor for service interruptions of public WiFi network services over 29 Community Centers in Seattle, with a total of 72 Cisco Meraki's Access Points (MR32) that provides service for over 30k users monthly.
- Make recommendations and implement as possible and approved, systems to simplify troubleshooting, prevent technical support and security problems, enable centralized management, support, and reporting.
- Maintain an inventory of computers, software, peripherals, and related equipment and materials.
- Track and produce reports on maintenance.
- Provide first line of troubleshooting to resolve broadband Internet connection and network issues and coordinate resolution with Seattle IT. Contact ISP (Comcast and Waves) to resolve broadband connection issues.
- Collaborate with Seattle IT and the Parks Department in planning for system and support.
- Communicate procedures for reporting outages and responses, with consideration for procedures to notify appropriate staff where an outage interrupts delivery public services.
- Maintain monthly reporting on WiFi and Kiosk usage, providing individual site and summary data.
- Maintain the licensing for Provisio SiteKiosk and Cisco Meraki access point software and services managing dashboard and license keys necessary to manage the hardware and services.

### IT Support Coordinator | ASSOCIATED RECREATION COUNCIL Seattle, WA: May 2014 - Dec 2014

• Responsible for the installation, use, networking and maintenance of computers hardware (PC Compatibles, Laptops and MACs), printers (Matrix, Ink, Laser, Thermal, Multifunction, 3D and

Copier), software (O365/MS Office, Adobe Creative Cloud, Outlook Express, SharePoint, Microsoft Family Safety, Trend Micro antivirus) and computer-related technology (Audio and Video technology, NAS and VRs) in the computer labs and for the community kiosks.

- Primary contact and responsible for Wi-Fi Services in 29 Seattle's Community Centers including Remote access through Meraki's Portal and working together with the City of Seattle.
- Responsible for remote access and configuration for 21 public Kiosks through Site Remote Portal and working together with the City of Seattle.
- Cabling (Cat5, Cat6) for 7 Seattle's Community Centers.
- Responsible for AV troubleshoot and installations in 7 Seattle's Community Centers (HDMI, RCA, USB, Firewire connections, XLR, BNC, SDI).
- Responsible to contact ISP (Internet Service Providers) to troubleshoot Internet Issues.
- Loads and upgrades software; copies licensed software; implement file backups; configure systems and applications.
- Install, configure and maintain Linksys routers and local area networks.
- Conduct first-line troubleshooting of computers and peripherals arranges for repair and maintenance as necessary, perform some hardware maintenance.
- Creator of Cloud storage to maintain inventories of computers, software, peripherals, and related equipment and materials.
- Move and recycle (Surplus) computers and pieces of equipment as necessary.
- Provides computer training to staff, volunteers and student as needed.
- Leads a team of staff and community partners to update the strategic technology plan for the computer labs and kiosks on as needed basis.
- Develops strong vendor relationships and negotiating strategic alliances.
- Develops and sets technology standards for the coalition; manage technology purchasing process.
- Effective communication to a range of financial supporters, volunteers, and partners.
- Perform other related duties as assigned by the supervisor.

#### IT Manager | Bellevue Presbyterian Church

Bellevue, WA: Jun 2012 - Nov 2013

- Provide all employees with fast, and efficient support based on best practices for delivering IT Services (ITIL)
- PC/Mac Desktop & Laptop support
- Purchase and install numerous types of hardware including Printers, Routers, Modems, Switchers, Firewalls and Wireless Access Points
- Install and support all types of PC software including antivirus programs and e-mail applications
- Design and install wiring for Data and Voice (Cat5e, Cat6), T1 Circuits, and Security Cameras
- Evaluate and purchase all new computer systems, software, and phone equipment
- Serve as Network Administrator for 100+ users, using Remote Access to perform troubleshooting
- Manage all Wireless Networks (setup and ongoing functionality) for the facility
- Administer the corporate Data Servers and Print Servers (setup, support, and system upgrades)
- Administer MS Exchange Server (create and maintain all organizational email accounts)
- Working with Active Directory.

# Technical Support Technician | DH INTERNATIONAL LLC

Renton, WA: Jan 2010 - Jun 2012

- Supported a wide range of Computers (Desktops, Laptops), Printers (All-in-One, Laser, Ink Jet and Matrix), Phone Systems (Analog & T1), Infrared Devices, Routers, Modems and Switchers
- Handled all Antivirus, Email and Business Software installation and configuration
- Wired companies for Data and Voice (Cat5e) networks
- Handled Audio and Video needs, including TV and Monitor troubleshooting

### Warehouse Associate/IT Support | AMERISOURCEBERGEN CORPORATION Kent, WA: Mar 2008 - Sep 2008

- Assisted with inventory and merchandise receiving duties in a warehouse environment
- Ensured compliance with all appropriate policies, procedures, safety rules and DEA regulations
- Handled order fulfillment, stocking, replenishment, and outbound shipping of customer orders
- Printed invoices and performed computer and printer maintenance
- Received Forklift Operation training

#### **IT Support Specialist** | Northwest Delivery Systems

Kent, WA: Oct 2003 - Mar 2008

- Supported the corporate network: Security and Virus Protection, Data Backup and Recovery
- Performed computer repairs (Desktops/Laptops) as well as software upgrades
- Repaired all hardware problems: scanners and matrix, inkjet and laser printers

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE (CONT'D)

#### IT Support Manager | HARDWARE MAINTENANCE & SERVICE

Lima, Peru: Feb 1999 – Jul 2003

- Managed a team of 10 Technicians
- Managed Information Systems for various clients of this computer consulting firm
- Monitored and maintained a multi-platform network operating system based on Windows NT and Windows 2000 Server
- Acted as Helpdesk for 60+ workstations, troubleshooting all end-user software/hardware issues
- Repaired Desktops, Laptops and various Printer types
- Installed, upgraded, and trained users in the proper usage of various software applications

# ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE

#### IT Support Specialist | HARDWARE MAINTENANCE & SERVICE

Lima, Peru: Jul 1993 – Feb 1999

Technology & Networking Services Consultancy

#### **IT Support Specialist** | Computer Engineering Services

Lima, Peru: Oct 1989 – Jul 1993

IT Support Services Firm—Division of IBM

#### **Computer Assembler & Circuit Designer** | NOVOTECH

Lima, Peru: Feb 1988 – Oct 1989

PC Sales & Networking Services Organization

## **EDUCATION & TRAINING**

#### **B.S. Degree in Electronics Engineering** | Ricardo Palma University

1988

Graduated in top third of class

#### **Computer Hardware and Software Repair Certificate** | Computer Engineering Service

1993

Additional Training & Coursework:

- SharePoint Training (2012 -2013)
- Forklift Operator Training & Certification | Amerisource Bergen Corporation (2008)
- Scanner Operation Classes | Northwest Delivery Systems (2004-2005)

# ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Languages: Fluent in English and Spanish

Hobbies: Fitness, running, reading, and soccer

Volunteerism: Red Cross (Certified in First Aid) & Spanish Translation (Bellevue Presbyterian

Church and Jubilee Reach, Bellevue, WA)
IT Support (South Park Neighborhood Center)
IT Support and Artistic Activities (Ballet Bellevue)

Soccer Assistant for Junior High Girls Team 2018-2019 (Bellevue Christian School) Logistics Leader at Meal Packing Marathon 2019 (Bellevue Presbyterian Church)

Awards: Star Performer Award 2017 (Associated Recreation Council)